one chapter 22 of Black Beauty this liox recording is in the public domain Black
Beauty by Anna Su Part two chapter 22 ear's Hall The next morning after breakfast
Joe put Mery legs into the mistress's low shase to take him to the vicarage; he
came first and said goodbye to us, and Mery leg Ned to us from the yard. Then
John put the saddle on Ginger and the leading rain on me, and rode us across
the country about 15 mil to 's Hall Park, where the L of
lived. There was a very fine house and a great deal of
stabling. We went into the yard through a stone gateway, and John asked for Mr. York.
It was some time before he came. He was a fine looking middle-aged man, and his
voice said at once that he expected to be obeyed. He was very friendly and polite
to Jon and after giving us a slight look he called the groom to take us to our
boxes, and invited Jon to take some refreshment. We were taken to a light,
airy stable, and placed in boxes joining each other, where we were rubbed down and
fed. In about half an hour John and Mr.
York, who was to be our new coachman, came in to see
us. “Now, Mr Manley he said, after carefully looking at us both, “I can see no fault in
these horses; but we all know that horses have their peculiarities as well as men,
and that sometimes they need different treatment. I should like to know if there
is anything particular in either of these that you would like to
mention.” “Well,” said John, “I don't believe there is a better pair of horses in the
country I'm right grieved I am to part with them, but they are not alike. The
black one is the most perfect temper I ever knew; I suppose he has never known a
hard word or blow since he was F and all
his pleasure seems to be to do what you wish; but the chestnut, I fancy, must have
had bad treatment; we heard as much from the dealer. She came to a snappish and
suspicious, but when she found what sort of place ours was, it all went off by
degrees; for 3 years I have never seen the smallest sign of temper, and if she
is well treated there is not a better, more willing animal than she is. But she
is now naturally a more irritable constitution than the black horse; flies
tease her more; anything wrong in the harness frets her more; and if she were
ill used or unfairly treated she would not be unlikely to give tit for tat. You
know that many high metal horses will do so.” “Of course,” said yor I quite understand;
but you know it is not easy in stables like these to have all the grooms just
what they should be. I do my best, and there I must leave it. I'll remember what
you have said about the May They were going out of the stable, when
John stopped and said, “I had better mention that we have never used the
check rain with either of them; the black horse never had one on, and the dealer
said it was the gag bit that spoiled the others temper.” “Well,” said York, “if they come here
they must wear the check rain I prefer a loose rain myself, and his lordship is
always very reasonable about horses; but my lady— —that's another thing; she will
have style, and if her carriage horse is not rained uptight she wouldn't look at
them. I always stand out against the gag bit and she'll do so, but it must be
tight up when my lady rides!” “I am sorry for it, very sorry,” said
Jon but I must go now, or I shall lose the
train.” He came round to each of us to pat
and speak to us for the last time; his voice sounded very
sad. I held my face close to him; that was
all I could do to say goodbye and then he was gone, and I have never seen him
since.
The next day Lord came to look at us; he seemed pleased with our
appearance. “I have great confidence in these horses,” he said, “from the character
my friend Mr. Gordon has given me of them.
Of course they are not a matching color, but my idea is that they will do very
well for the carriage while we are in the country. Before we go to London I
must try to match Baron; the black horse, I believe, is perfect for
riding.” York then told him what JN had said about us.
“Well,” said he, “you must keep an eye to the
mayor and put the check rain easy; I dare say they all do very well with a little
humoring at first. I'll mention it to your lady.” In the afternoon we were harnessed
and put in the carriage, and as the stable clock struck three we were led
round to the front of the house. It was all very grand, and three or
four times as large as the old house at Berwick but not half so pleasant, if a
horse may have an opinion.
Two footmen were standing ready, dressed in drab livery, with scarlet breaches and white
stockings. Presently we heard the rustling sound of silk as my lady came
down the flight of stone steps. She stepped around to look at us; she was a
tall proud looking woman, and did not seem pleased about something, but she
said nothing, and got into the carriage. This was the first time of
wearing a check rain and I must say, though it certainly was a nuisance not
to be able to get my head down there now
and then, it did not pull my head higher than I was accustomed to carry it. I felt
anxious about Ginger, but she seemed to be quiet and
content. The next day at 3:00 we were again at the door, and the footman as
before; we heard the silk dress Russell and the lady came down the steps, and in
an imperious voice she said, “York, you must put those horses' heads higher; they
are not fit to be seen.” York got down, and said very
respectfully, “I beg your pardon, my lady, but these horses have not been rained up
for 3 years, and my lord said it would be
safer to bring them to it by degrees; but if your ladyship pleases I can take them
up a little more.” “Do so,” she said. York came round to our heads and
shortened the rain himself— —one hole, I think; every little makes a difference, be
it for better or worse, and that day we
had a steep hill to go up. Then I began to understand what I had heard of. Of
course, I wanted to put my head forward and take the carriage up with a will, as
we had been used to do; but no, I had to
pull with my head up now, and that took all the spirit out of me, and the strain
came on my back and legs. When we came in Ginger said, “Now you
see what it is like; but this is not bad,
and if it does not get much worse than this I shall say nothing about it, for we
are very well treated here; but if they strain me up tight, why, let them look out!
I can't bear it, and I won't.” Day by day whole by whole our bearing
Reigns were shortened, and instead of looking forward with pleasure to having
my harness put on, as I used to do, I began to dread it. Ginger, too, seemed
restless, though she said very little. At last I thought the worst was
over; for several days there was no more shortening, and I determined to make the
best of it and do my duty, though it was now a constant harass instead of a
pleasure; but the worst was not yet come
end of chapter